# **SATYASHEEL** ASSISTANT VICE PRESIDENT-DELIVERY & TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS

+91 98305 85832 | SATYASHEEL@HOTMAIL.COM | LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SATYASHEEL | NEW DELHI (INDIA)

## **QUALIFICATION SUMMARY**

Business and technology consulting leader having 20+ years of industry experience with a demonstrated ability to develop C-suite relationships and operate in both a startup and mature market environments. A consistent and extensive experience in the sphere of managing multiple large scales and complex IT-enabled transformation programs from strategy through execution in business, and technology domains with significant shareholder impact.

Awarded and recognized for thought leadership, delivery of innovative solutions, understanding of technology and its meaningful application, ability to deliver under adverse conditions and coping with extreme pressure. Brings an expert's understanding of underlying business drivers, processes, technologies, and organizational relationships across clients in Travel/Transportation, Smarter Cities, Public/Government, and Banking/Finance sectors across emerging and mature markets.

## **SPECIALITIES**

- Management Consulting, Application
   Services/Management, System Integration,
   Transition/Transformation, Digital
   Transformation/Strategy, Smarter Cities
- Program/Account/Vendor Management,
   PMO, Agile Transformation, P&L
- Presales, Driving New Evolving Technology Trends & Innovation Strategy, Automation, & People Management
- Managing Contractual Relationships, Bid Management,
   Planning & Forecasting, & Stakeholders Relations.
- Technology: Enterprise Integration/ Middleware (IBM WMB/ESB), SOA/BPM/Cloud/Mobile.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Assistant Vice President - Delivery & Technology / Mantra Softech Pvt Ltd

Jun 2019 - Ongoing

Leading the conceptualization of the overall delivery strategy & execution of (Indian) government defense account & System Integration engagements- including governance model, customer & vendor engagement, P&L, & continuous improvement programs.

#### **Director / Akscellence Info Solutions**

Dec 2017 - June 2019

- Engaged in helping build the start-up organization and focus on Digital.
- Client Strategy Consulting Provided roadmaps and periodic recommendations to the client's overall goals by analyzing strengths and areas needing improvement.
- Executive responsibility in providing the oversight and leadership in delivery management, Process & Tools, including mentoring.

## Senior Manager / Ericsson

Apr 2016 - Nov 2017

- Served as a customer single point of contact, owning overall responsibility of contracted services, ensuring expected services were delivered and issues were addressed at the right priority level.
- Led RFPs/Proposal write-up for large clients in project management processes & tools.
- Driven Project Management competency to improvise the PM Process Development towards mitigating
  delivery risks, recommending the use/development of automation tools for improving the cost & resource
  optimization or reuse as an asset, and standardizing the processes, tools & templates.

- Responsible for Base Account Growth including Client-CSAT, deliverables, account receivables, & new business. Aided in signing > USD 10 M in new business.
- Led new business development activities such as RFPs & proposals. Engaged in prep strategic activities, proposal reviews, and start-up activities.
- Served as the business area & delivery review representative from the government & public sector to the various new and ongoing Complex Program and Projects.
- Responsible for Revenue & Profitability of the engagement by identifying growth opportunities & cost optimization levers. Reduced delivery costs by over \$10M, using resource optimization & argumentation.
- Established & led program business rhythms to monitor program technical & financial status, includes internal customer and senior business unit reviews.
- Assessed new emerging technologies and make recommendations for improvement and efficiency, including driving innovation and automation initiatives for project management & tools practice across the organization.
- Participated in organization staffing, includes employee recruitment, training, career development, performance assessment, workload planning, recognition, salary, and disciplinary actions.
- Mentored and trained other projects/program managers and pre-sales team.

Senior Software Engineer / Tech Mahindra (Erstwhile, Satyam Computer)

Mar 2001- Nov 2003

### **EDUCATION**

- Executive Program in Business Management (EPBM) / Indian Institute of Management, Calcutta
- B.E., Computer Engineering / Nagpur University, Nagpur
- High School / Delhi Public School, Bokaro Steel City

#### PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS & CERTIFICATIONS

- Member of Institution of Engineers (India) Limited
- IBM Project Management Certification

## **AWARDS**

- IBM Orion Award (Eminence & Excellence) for Business Commitment & Relentlessly reinvent IBM and Client consecutively for 2014 and 2015, respectively.
- Managers' Choice Award from IBM India for Put the Client First and Unite to get it Done Now consecutively for 2014 and 2015, respectively.
- IBM Ovation Award for ACSA project- South Africa.
- IBM Bravo Award for IBM Organization Initiatives, Unilever Netherlands project, & Air Canada project for the year 2007, 2006 and 2005, respectively.
- IBM Customer Dedication Award.
- IBM Special Performance Bonus Award for Top Individual Performance.
- IBM Basic Blue for New Leaders for Leadership.
- Leader Readiness award in IBM in recognition of leading a high performance.
- IBM Top Technical Talent award.